# Benjamin Sampica

I currently work as a Web Application Developer for Polk County in Des Moines and have been since 2016.

I utilize SQL, C#, EF, and LINQ to create .NET MVC web applications in various browser languages that help Polk County better serve its residents

I graduated from the University of Northern Iowa with a bachelor's degree in Management Information Systems in May of 2016. also graduated in 2012 with a associate's degree as a Computer Support Specialist.

View my portfolio and code that I've written at www.benjaminsampica.com.

## Professional Skills

HTMI. Expert Advanced Entity Framework Core Advanced Bootstrap 4 Advanced Advanced Bootstrap 3 Advanced JIRA C# Intermediate .NET Intermediate LINO Intermediate Entity Framework 5 Intermediate Intermediate Intermediate Javascript Git Intermediate MySQL Competent

### Freelance Projects

Zy Universe - www.zyuniverse.com

Built using MVC6, EF Core, Bootstrap 4, and JQuery lazy loading, Zy Universe (code name 'Cookie') is a 2.5D arena shooter game.

The site queries Facebook, Blogger, and Youtube API's to pull content in dynamically directly from social media.

Angela Connolly - www.angelaconnolly.org

Built using MVC5, EF 5, and Bootstrap 3, Angela Connolly is Polk County's current Board of Supervisor for District 2.

It utilizes Facebook API to pull content directly from her public Facebook page and also links with ShareBlue, a fundraising organization for politicians.

The site received thousands of unique visitors and was responsible for tens of thousands of dollars in donations during the 2018 election. After the election was won the site was taken offline and is pending re-purposing as an incumbent site.

## Hobbies & Interests

#### Computers

I'm a hardware enthusiast at heart and enjoy following the computer hardware scene. I've custom built dozens of computers over the years and each time I try to one-up myself.

#### Exercise

I've been playing racquetball since my dad got me into it over a decade ago. It's great exercise and I love the dynamic challenge of speed, skill, and strategy. I also run the IMT and Dam to Dam half marathons in Des Moines

# Education

University of Northern Iowa Management Information Systems Cedar Falls Iowa Graduated May 2016

Officer of UNIPAWWSH (charity group). Officer of UNISTARR (Student rights group).

Kirkwood Community College Computer Support Specialist Cedar Rapids Iowa Graduated December 2012

## Employment History

Polk County Web Application Developer Des Moines Iowa

June 2016 - Present

- Full-stack development starting with gathering requirements/existing workflows through front-end implementation with client acceptance.
- Use cloud source control (Bitbucket  $\mbox{\em w/}$  Sourcetree) and peer code review for all development.
- Utilize Agile processes like sprints, team backlog grooming sessions, story points, and scrum boards (JIRA).
- Continuous Improvement through upgrading projects from MVC4/MVC5 to MVC 6 when time/necessity allow.
- Extending Bootstrap 3 and 4 with custom CSS/JS solutions to match client needs
- Created and actively developing/maintaining Polk County's web-based staff scheduler program. This includes calculating and tracking accruals, scheduling hours, exporting payroll, scheduling employee time off as well as providing consumable, interactive calendar views for employees and supervisors alike among a laundry list of features.
- Creating/Actively developing a web-based case manager system for the Polk County Sheriff which includes dynamic document generation, geolocating and address retrieval through Google API, a double-entry accounting system, and e-filer with Selenium through the State of Iowa website for returns of service

The Members Group IT Service Coordinator

Urbandale Iowa

January 2016 - June 2016

- Took Help Desk Support calls and logged tickets.
- Resolved Tier 1 Tier 3 (Non-Application Development) tickets.
- Trained incoming Tier 1 employees on common issues and application-specific workflows.

Mercer IT Intern Urbandale Iowa

May 2015 - August 2015

- Updated, created, and maintained company SharePoint sites.
- Led project to create a SharePoint consistency template among team sites.
- Created automation scripts with Selenium in Java for large-scale automation testing.
- Wrote documentation for SharePoint from both a users and developers point of view.
- Updated VBA-based software to improve search accuracy and added in new systems.



